&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：你们中的一些人无疑已经看过Wat了
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Some of you have undoubtedly seen the WAT
我多次提到的视频，
video I referred to multiple times,
Wat视频中最著名的事情之一就是，像这样的东西
and one of the famous things in the WAT video was, how could something like
空数组不知何故强制等于自身的否定？
an empty array somehow be coercively equal to the negation of itself?
从表面上看，这个问题的构建方式，
And on its surface, the way that problem is constructed,
这似乎是反对JavaScript的明确论据，并且
it seems like a clear arguments against JavaScript, and
反对双重等同的明确论据。
a clear arguments against the double equals.
但这并不是看起来的那样，这不是看起来的那样，
But this is not as it seems, this is not as it appears,
因为这个构造一开始就是一个错误的构造。
because this construct is a false construct to begin with.
你永远不会，在任何情况下，
You would never, under any circumstances,
永远不要将一个值与自身的否定进行比较。
compare a value to the negation of itself, ever.
这在节目中永远不会发生。
That's just never gonna happen in the programs.
所以我们去找
So we went and looked for
这种人为的场景在真正的代码中永远不会发生。
this artificial scenario that would never happen in real code.
然后说这个机制被打破是因为一个奇怪的角落案件
And then said this whole mechanism is broken because one weird corner case
行为不明智。
doesn't behave sensibly.
在什么情况下你会有一个数组，并且
Under what circumstances would you ever have an array, and
然后尝试将其与数组的否定进行比较？
then try to compare it to the negation of the array?
否定任何数组，而不仅仅是它本身，任何数组？
Negation of any array, not just itself, of any array?
这永远不会明智地发生，你永远不会像那样设计代码。
That would never sensibly occur, you would never design code like that.
不过，让我们解释一下它是如何工作的。
Nevertheless, let's explain how it works.
它会用到和我教过你的一模一样的东西。
It's gonna use the exact same stuff I already taught you.
如果我有两个数组，出于某种奇怪的原因，
If I had two arrays, and for some strange reason,
我试图将一个数组与其自身的否定进行比较。
I tried to compare one array to the negation of itself.
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：将你心中的那个与更合适的比较进行比较，
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Compare that in your mind to the more appropriate comparison,
也就是说，我想检查它们是否是相同的数组。
which is to say, I want to check to see if they're not the same array.
那是不相等的。
That's the not equals.
这些看起来可能是一样的东西，但这些是完全不同的方法。
Those might look like the same thing, but these are entirely different approaches.
一种是说我想看看它是否强制性地等于它的否定，并且
One is saying I wanna see if it is coercively equal to its negation, and
另一个是说我想看看它是不是强制平等的。
the other one is saying I wanna see if it is not coercively equal.
那些是完全不同的野兽。
Those are entirely different beasts.
第8行是您将在代码中明智地编写的内容。
Line 8 is what you would write in code sensibly.
第4行，WAT视频源本质上是您永远不会用代码编写的内容。
Line 4, the WAT video source, essentially, is what you would never write in code.
但让我们放纵一下。
But let's just indulge it for a moment.
为了解释算法，我们怎么解释第四行允许它
To explain the algorithm, how are we gonna explain that line four allows it and
八号线还允许吗？
also line eight allows it?
这两件事怎么可能都是真的呢？
How is it possible that both of those can be true?
嗯，这是发挥作用的算法。
Well, here's the algorithm at play.
第一，我们从工作坊开始，第一个学生不是，或者
Number one, we start with the workshop one students not, or
等于否定了车间的两个学生。
equal to the negation of the workshop two students.
我们要做的是减少Workshop1学生的价值，
What we have to do is reduce workshop1Students to its value,
它是一个数组，然后取反workshop2Students，
which is an array, and then negate workshop2Students,
workshop2Students是一个真实的数组。
workshop2Students is an array which is truthy.
所以如果我们否定它变成第五行，它就变成假的，对吗？
So if we negate it becomes line five, it becomes false, right?
现在，我们有一个非原语，与原语相比。
Now, we have a non-primitive compared to a primitive.
所以我们需要将非原语转化为原语。
So we need to turn that non-primitive into a primitive.
我们需要将数组转换为基元，它会变成什么？
We need to turn the array into a primitive and what does it become?
它成为空字符串。
It becomes the empty string.
所以现在，我们有一个空字符串与false相比。
So now, we have an empty string compared to false.
我们有两个原语，但它们的类型不同。
We have two primitives but they are not of the same type.
算法更喜欢把它们都变成数字，所以
The algorithm prefers that they both become numbers, so
这个变成了一个数字，但它不应该。
this one becomes a number, which it shouldn't.
但它确实变成了数字零而不是纳米，而这个需要成为
But it does become the number zero instead of nano and this one needs to become
一个数字，现在零等于零，好吗？
a number as well and now zero is equal to zero, okay?
算法的应用是明智的，但是
The algorithm is sensibly applied, but
它出现在一个虚假的角落案例中，而这种情况在您的代码中根本不会发生。
it's on a bogus corner case that would never actually happen in your code.
所以这不是反对这个机制的有效论据。
So it's not an effective argument against this mechanism.
它制作了很棒的视频和头条，但是
It makes for great videos and great headlines but
这不是一个理性的论点。
it is not a rational argument.
第二个更合理，因为如果我们看一下等价物
The second one is much more rational, because if we look at the equivalent
对于不平等，它基本上就像是对强制平等的否定。
of the not equals, it is basically like the negation of the coercive equality.
所以我们可以问自己，这是否有意义
So we can ask ourselves, does it make sense for
工作坊一的学生比工作坊二的学生要强吗？
workshop one students to be coercively compared to workshop two students?
好吧，因为它们都是数组，
Well, since they're both arrays,
那么我们实际上所做的就是问一个身份问题。
then what we're effectively doing is asking an identity question.
我们是说，他们不是同一个身份吗？
We're saying, are they not the same identity?
这是一个完全有效的事情，你可以在你的程序中要求。
Which is a totally valid thing for you to ask in your program.
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：如果您使用三重等于，它将同样工作
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: And it would work identically if you use the triple equals
他们的版本。
version of them.
这是一件理性的事情，而且
It's a rational thing, and
在有理数的情况下，双等数和三等数之间没有区别。
it has no difference in the rational case between double equals and triple equals.